<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cloud of points | Jacques-Olivier Lachaud</title>
    <link>https://www.lama.univ-savoie.fr/pagesmembres/lachaud/public/tag/cloud-of-points/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.lama.univ-savoie.fr/pagesmembres/lachaud/public/tag/cloud-of-points/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>cloud of points</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.lama.univ-savoie.fr/pagesmembres/lachaud/public/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>cloud of points</title>
      <link>https://www.lama.univ-savoie.fr/pagesmembres/lachaud/public/tag/cloud-of-points/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>StableProxies</title>
      <link>https://www.lama.univ-savoie.fr/pagesmembres/lachaud/public/project/stable-proxies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.lama.univ-savoie.fr/pagesmembres/lachaud/public/project/stable-proxies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Start date: Feb. 2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objective of the project is to propose new calculus models for the
geometry processing of large, heterogeneous and complex geometrical
objects. The targeted geometrical models (polygonal meshes, point
clouds, surfaces of voxel sets) are usually defective for direct
geometry processing: deficient or missing topology,
self-intersections, holes, non-manifold parts, perturbations,
outliers. Their common characteristic is to be approximations of an
underlying smooth object and not an interpolation of its boundary. Our
approach is to build stable geometric proxies (embedded in a regular
lattice) for these various data, for two main goals: first to
guarantee that the estimates or the results of the calculus are
theoretically accurate or stable (when compared to their counterpart
from the continuous analysis), second to design practical algorithms
that scale well in terms of performance, numerical stability,
capability to represent various dimensional objects (volumes,
surfaces, 1d curves in space), and memory efficiency (thanks to a
multiscale approach). This unified approach provides generic tools to
measure quantities and perform calculus on such discrete data, and
allows modeling and simulation of complex and natural phenomena on
various real geometric data. We will more specifically explore
applications in material engineering (analysis and calculus on high
resolution volumetric surfaces from micro-tomographic images, fracture
simulation on materials&amp;hellip;), the geometry processing of acquired
massive, highly detailed, 3D point clouds (e.g, billions of points
acquired with LiDAR or photogrammetry).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
